const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A neonate is brought to the emergency department with respiratory distress two hours after birth. He was born post-term at 42+6 weeks of gestation and the labor was prolonged and difficult. There is a greenish hue to his skin and the separated umbilical cord. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Neonatal respiratory distress syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Transient tachypnea of the newborn","bool":false},{"option":"Sepsis","bool":false},{"option":"Meconium aspiration syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which one of these is a synthetic form of estrogen?","answers":[{"option":"Estetrol","bool":false},{"option":"Estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Ethinyl estradiol","bool":true},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false},{"option":"Estriol","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which one of these is a natural form of estrogen?","answers":[{"option":"Ethinyl estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Estradiol valerate","bool":false},{"option":"Levonorgestrel","bool":false},{"option":"Medroxyprogesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Estradiol","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the pathophysiology of hirsutism in polycystic ovarian syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Excessive cortisol production","bool":false},{"option":"Excessive androgen production","bool":true},{"option":"Medication overuse","bool":false},{"option":"Excessive estrogen production","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal hyperplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of these is not a germ cell tumor?","answers":[{"option":"Sertoli cell tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Seminoma","bool":false},{"option":"Choriocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Teratoma","bool":false},{"option":"Yolk sac tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A woman with a twin pregnancy has successfully delivered her first baby vaginally. If the other fetus is in a transverse lie, what is the next best step?","answers":[{"option":"Cesarean section","bool":false},{"option":"Breech extraction","bool":false},{"option":"External cephalic version","bool":true},{"option":"Await spontaneous delivery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal podalic version","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 20-year-old woman develops a left-sided ovarian mass. Workup for malignancy reveals a tumor that over-expressed the receptor tyrosine kinase, KIT. Which of these is the odd one out for this tumor?","answers":[{"option":"Ovarian counterpart of seminoma","bool":false},{"option":"Well defined cell boundaries","bool":false},{"option":"Schiller-Duval body","bool":true},{"option":"Sheets of cells with clear cytoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Central nuclei","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following tumors is comprised of adult neural tissue, sebaceous material, and hair shafts?","answers":[{"option":"Immature teratoma","bool":false},{"option":"Struma ovarii","bool":false},{"option":"Dysgerminoma","bool":false},{"option":"Mature teratoma","bool":true},{"option":"Yolk sac tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 24-year-old woman presents with a soft solitary nodule on her face. Biopsy reveals a granulomatous lesion with a necrotic center. She is sexually active with multiple partners. Which of the following sexually transmitted organisms can cause this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Human papilloma virus","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":true},{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomonas vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 26-year-old-woman presents with a complaint of grayish foul-smelling vaginal discharge for the past 5 days. Her vulva is clear with no complaints of pain or itching. Laboratory evaluation reveals a pH of 5. Which of the following features is characteristic of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Giant cells","bool":false},{"option":"Budding yeasts","bool":false},{"option":"Flagellated trophozoite","bool":false},{"option":"Clue cells","bool":true},{"option":"Cervical dysplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following pathogenic factors of Neisseria gonorrheae help in its attachment to mucosal surfaces?","answers":[{"option":"Microvilli","bool":false},{"option":"Pili","bool":true},{"option":"Cilia","bool":false},{"option":"Flagella","bool":false},{"option":"Stereocilia","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 1-week-old neonate presents with irritability, poor feeding, and fever for 3 days. Physical examination reveals a respiratory rate of 72 breaths/minute with a bulging fontanelle. Mother had a history of leakage of amniotic fluid 24 hours before delivery. What is the most likely cause of neonatal illness?","answers":[{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false},{"option":"Toxoplasma gondii","bool":false},{"option":"Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 7-week-old infant presents with jaundice for 11 days. Physical examination reveals hepatosplenomegaly with yellowish discoloration of skin and sclera. Ultrasound abdomen reveals an absent gall bladder. What is the most likely underlying etiology?","answers":[{"option":"Viral hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Choledocholithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Dubin-Johnson syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Gilbert syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Biliary atresia","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"According to the WHO, what is the minimum number of antenatal visits required?","answers":[{"option":"4","bool":true},{"option":"5","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"10","bool":false},{"option":"7","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the correct terminology for children under 28 days of age?","answers":[{"option":"Infant","bool":false},{"option":"Fetus","bool":false},{"option":"Neonate","bool":true},{"option":"School going","bool":false},{"option":"Preschool","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A woman enters premature labor due to infection of the fetal membranes. What is the best intervention?","answers":[{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":true},{"option":"Tocolytics and corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Tocolytics","bool":false},{"option":"NSAIDs","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the best description for koilocytes?","answers":[{"option":"Clear cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cells with little cytoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Small cells with high mitotic activity","bool":false},{"option":"Cells with perinuclear halo","bool":true},{"option":"Cells with birbeck granules","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A woman experiences mild shortness of breath in her daily routine work. What is the stage of her disease according to the NYHA classification?","answers":[{"option":"Class 4","bool":false},{"option":"Class 1","bool":false},{"option":"Class 2","bool":true},{"option":"Class 5","bool":false},{"option":"Class 3","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A woman has vulvar cancer that has spread to the inguinofemoral nodes. What is the stage of her tumor?","answers":[{"option":"Stage 2","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 1A","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 3","bool":true},{"option":"Stage 4","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 1B","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the main modality of treatment for vulvar cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Radiotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal surgical excision","bool":false},{"option":"Palliative care","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Radical surgical excision","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 56-year-old woman is being evaluated for an ovarian mass. Her sister has a positive BRCA1 mutation. What is the associated risk with this mutation?","answers":[{"option":"Increased risk of vulvar cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Increased risk of cervical cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Increased risk of ovarian cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Increased risk of lung cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Increased risk of colon cancer","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which one of these non-seminomatous germ cell tumors contains Schiller-Duval bodies?","answers":[{"option":"Yolk-sac tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Leydig cell tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Choriocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cell tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Dysgerminoma","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the effect of hemophilia A on bleeding and prothrombin time (PT)?","answers":[{"option":"Increased PT and normal bleeding time","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased PT and bleeding time","bool":false},{"option":"Increased bleeding time and PT","bool":false},{"option":"Normal bleeding time and PT","bool":true},{"option":"Increased bleeding time and normal PT","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which one of these is not a manifestation of chronic liver disease?","answers":[{"option":"Jaundice","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolytic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Bleeding diathesis","bool":false},{"option":"Ascites","bool":false},{"option":"Spider angiomas","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A baby swallows maternal blood during delivery and later passes it on in stool. Which of the following terms describe this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Hematochezia","bool":false},{"option":"Meconium ileus","bool":false},{"option":"Volvulus","bool":false},{"option":"Necrotizing entercolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Melena neonatorum","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which one of these is an appropriate sign for placental abruption?","answers":[{"option":"Painless vaginal bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Ascites","bool":false},{"option":"Tense abdomen","bool":true},{"option":"Soft abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Fever","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A baby in a longitudinal lie is being delivered. On vaginal examination, the presenting part is soft. What is the most likely presentation?","answers":[{"option":"Elbow presentation","bool":false},{"option":"Shoulder presentation","bool":false},{"option":"Back presentation","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalic presentation","bool":false},{"option":"Breech presentation","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the ideal method for emergency contraception 3 days after unprotected intercourse?","answers":[{"option":"Levonorgestrel IUS","bool":false},{"option":"Mifepristone","bool":false},{"option":"Ulipristal acetate pill","bool":false},{"option":"Copper IUD","bool":true},{"option":"Levonorgestrel pill","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the treatment for hirsutism?","answers":[{"option":"Metformin","bool":false},{"option":"Combined oral contraceptive pill","bool":false},{"option":"Clomiphene citrate","bool":false},{"option":"Eflornithine cream","bool":true},{"option":"GnRH analogue","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Semen fluid analysis from a 24-year-old man reveals 5 percent motile sperms. What term describes his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Asthenozoospermia","bool":true},{"option":"Teratoozoospermia","bool":false},{"option":"Oligozoospermia","bool":false},{"option":"Azoospermia","bool":false},{"option":"Normal semen","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the cause of uterus didelphys?","answers":[{"option":"Unilateral degeneration of mullerian duct","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of mesonephric duct fusion","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of mullerian duct fusion","bool":true},{"option":"Bilateral degeneration of mullerian duct","bool":false},{"option":"Partial fusion of mullerian duct","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which one of the following conditions is not associated with endometrial hyperplasia?","answers":[{"option":"Polycystic ovarian syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Granulosa cell tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Menopause","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone therapy","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the mechanism behind the formation of breast cysts?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in number of acini per lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in number of lobules","bool":false},{"option":"Dilation of lobules","bool":true},{"option":"Stromal fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Increased number of luminal cells in ducts","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A woman presents to the emergency with a hot and painful cyst on her labia major. What is the first step in management?","answers":[{"option":"Marsupialization","bool":false},{"option":"Incision and drainage","bool":true},{"option":"Sitz bath","bool":false},{"option":"Surgical excision","bool":false},{"option":"Oral antibiotics and send home","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 25-year-old married woman presents to the clinic with fever and lowers abdominal pain for the past 2 days. On pelvic examination, greenish purulent discharge is seen from inside the cervix. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Complete miscarraige","bool":false},{"option":"Red degeneration of fibroid","bool":false},{"option":"Endometriosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic inflammatory disease","bool":true},{"option":"Ruptured ectopic pregnancy","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 30-year-old woman recently underwent a total hysterectomy for a complete mole. What is the most appropriate laboratory investigation for a regular follow-up?","answers":[{"option":"Pelvic ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Serum β-hcG","bool":true},{"option":"Complete blood count (CBC)","bool":false},{"option":"Urinalysis","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal ultrasound","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the below enlisted is not associated with a complete molar pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Serum β-hcG levels greater than 100,000 mIU/L","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal parts palpable","bool":true},{"option":"Most common symptom is vaginal bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Overgrown villous trophoblast with cystic swollen villi","bool":false},{"option":"Snowstorm appearance on pelvic ultrasound","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 35-year-old lady consults her gynecologist with a complaint of irregular spotting between her menstrual cycles for the past 6 months. Examination under anesthesia (EUA) and biopsy reveal a cervical polyp measuring 2 cm. What is the treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Cryotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Cone biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Avulsion with ring forcep","bool":true},{"option":"Wertheim hysterectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Wait and watch","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 30-year-old female presents for her regular visit with her previous pap smear report which reveals mild dyskaryosis. What is the appropriate next step?","answers":[{"option":"Repeat smear in 6 months","bool":false},{"option":"Perform excisional or ablative procedure","bool":false},{"option":"Repeat smear in 2 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"Perform high-grade HPV testing","bool":true},{"option":"Colposcopy","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the usual duration of the menstrual phase?","answers":[{"option":"5-14 days","bool":false},{"option":"1-2 days","bool":false},{"option":"10-14 days","bool":false},{"option":"1-5 days","bool":true},{"option":"3-10 days","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"The spiral arteries become convoluted, and growth of the endometrium occurs under influence of estrogen and progesterone in which phase of the menstrual cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Menstrual phase","bool":false},{"option":"Proliferative phase","bool":false},{"option":"Luteal phase","bool":true},{"option":"Follicular phase","bool":false},{"option":"Ovulatory phase","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is considered a functional ovarian cyst?","answers":[{"option":"Mucinous cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Theca lutein cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus lutein cyst","bool":true},{"option":"Type I neoplastic cyst","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 13-year-old girl is brought by her mother to the clinic with concerns that she has no commenced her periods yet. On examination, she is a healthy 13-year-old with normal secondary sexual characteristics. A limited pelvic exam reveals a blind-ending vagina with an ultrasound abdomen revealing an absent uterus. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"XY gonadal dysgenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse vaginal septum","bool":false},{"option":"Androgen insensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Imperforate hymen","bool":false},{"option":"Mayer-Rokitansky-Küster-Hauser syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following medications suppresses follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) and luteinizing hormone (LH) release in the treatment of subfertility?","answers":[{"option":"Clomiphene citrate","bool":false},{"option":"Tamoxifen","bool":false},{"option":"Metformin","bool":false},{"option":"Gonadotropin analogues","bool":true},{"option":"Raloxifene","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 25-year-old female consults her general practitioner with the concern that she has had hair growing all over her body for the past year. What is the correct terminology for this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Virilization","bool":false},{"option":"Hirsutism","bool":false},{"option":"Lanugo","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrichosis","bool":true},{"option":"Androgenization","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of hirsutism in women of reproductive age group?","answers":[{"option":"Corticosteroid use","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic ovarian syndrome (PCOS)","bool":true},{"option":"Cushing syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Androgen insensitivity syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Androgen-secreting tumors","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 22-year-old female came to the clinic for a pap smear. Her results showed mild dyskaryosis and dysplasia involving less than 1/3 of the basal membrane. What is the next step in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Colposcopy, cytology after 6 months","bool":true},{"option":"Trachelectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Hysterectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Loop electrosurgical excision procedure (LEEP)","bool":false},{"option":"Large loop excision of transformation zone (LLETZ)","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 25-year-old woman is diagnosed with subserosal fibroids. She is married and wishes to soon start a family. What is the best treatment plan for her?","answers":[{"option":"No treatment until family complete","bool":false},{"option":"Hysterectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Myomectomy","bool":true},{"option":"Uterine artery embolization","bool":false},{"option":"Mefenamic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A pregnant woman is diagnosed with thalassemia minor trait. She is worried about her baby and wishes to know the chances of her baby being affected by this illness. What is the next best step to assess the risk?","answers":[{"option":"Husband's hemoglobin electrophoresis","bool":true},{"option":"Counselling that her baby is not at risk","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal hemoglobin electrophoresis","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal gene testing","bool":false},{"option":"Setting up more frequent followups","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A woman presents with post-partum hemorrhage, following the delivery of her baby at home 4 hours ago. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Retained products of conception","bool":false},{"option":"Genital trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine atony","bool":true},{"option":"Sepsis","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulation disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A newborn baby develops a swelling over his parietal bone following a forceps-assisted delivery. What is the most accurate statement for this type of swelling?","answers":[{"option":"Needs urgent drainage","bool":false},{"option":"It is soft and pits on pressure","bool":false},{"option":"It crosses the suture lines","bool":false},{"option":"It is superficial to the Galea aponeurotica","bool":false},{"option":"Will go away eventually","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A young girl presents with deepening of the voice and enlarged clitoris. What is the most accurate term that describes these changes?","answers":[{"option":"Feminization","bool":false},{"option":"Androgenization","bool":false},{"option":"Virilization","bool":true},{"option":"Hirsuitism","bool":false},{"option":"Puberty","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A woman is in a circulatory shock with minimal per vaginal bleeding, following the delivery of her baby. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Coagulopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Sepsis","bool":false},{"option":"Placental abruption","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine atony","bool":true},{"option":"Vaginal trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is also known as Bowen's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Warty neoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Genital warts","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Vulval intra-epithelial neoplasm","bool":true},{"option":"Condyloma acuminatum","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following features is not associated with a complete mole?","answers":[{"option":"46XX","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal parts present","bool":true},{"option":"No fetal parts seen","bool":false},{"option":"All villi are oedematous","bool":false},{"option":"Associated with choriocarcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is a functional cyst?","answers":[{"option":"Dermoid cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Luteoma","bool":false},{"option":"Serous cysts","bool":false},{"option":"Follicular cyst","bool":true},{"option":"Endometriotic cysts","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following correctly describes struma ovarii?","answers":[{"option":"Germ cell tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Epithelial tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Serous tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Sex cord stromal tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Metastatic tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following often occurs in combination with yolk sac tumors?","answers":[{"option":"Teratoma","bool":false},{"option":"Choriocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Seminoma","bool":false},{"option":"Gonadoblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Embryonal carcinoma","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is seen on immunohistological staining of a yolk sac tumor?","answers":[{"option":"LDH","bool":false},{"option":"Beta hCG","bool":false},{"option":"PLAP","bool":false},{"option":"AFP","bool":true},{"option":"OCT 3","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 29-year-old woman, 5 days post-partum, presents to the clinic with the complaint of painful breasts. Examination shows cracks and fissures on the nipple and the breast is warm to touch. Which organism is most probably responsible for this?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is also known as Zuska disease?","answers":[{"option":"Periareolar mastitis","bool":false},{"option":"Periductal mastitis","bool":true},{"option":"Granulomatous mastitis","bool":false},{"option":"Sclerosing lymphocytic lobulitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute mastitis","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 32-year-old female presents to the clinic with complaints of painful breasts. Her history is significant for smoking. Which of the following key feature is related to her diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Radial sclerosing lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Atrophic ducts and lobules with thickened basement membranes","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous metaplasia of lactiferous ducts","bool":true},{"option":"Dilation of lobules","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 22-year-old female comes to your clinic complaining of a mass in her right breast. She denies smoking and has no family history of breast cancer. Her history reveals a road traffic accident 2 weeks ago. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphocytic mastopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroadenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute mastitis","bool":false},{"option":"Fat necrosis","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 39 weeks pregnant female has ruptured membranes, and a diagnosis of normal labor is made at the maternity clinic. She is 7 cm dilated and has regular contractions; each lasting for 15-20 seconds. What is the preferred management?","answers":[{"option":"Ventouse","bool":false},{"option":"Forceps delivery","bool":false},{"option":"One-on-one midwifery care","bool":true},{"option":"Episiotomy","bool":false},{"option":"C section","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 4-year-old girl presents with a grape-like mass protruding from her vagina. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphangioma","bool":false},{"option":"Nephroblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Leiomyosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Embryonal rhabdomyosarcoma","bool":true},{"option":"Hemangioma","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 22-week pregnant woman presents with severe bleeding and abdominal pain. What is the first step of management?","answers":[{"option":"Two large bore IV cannulae","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"ABCDE approach","bool":true},{"option":"Abdominal examination","bool":false},{"option":"Vaginal examination","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 12-week pregnant woman presents with vaginal bleeding and abdominal pain. On examination, the cervical os is closed and the fetal heartbeat is present. What is the ideal management?","answers":[{"option":"Intravenous methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Vaccum aspiration","bool":false},{"option":"Dilation and evacuation","bool":false},{"option":"Expectant","bool":true},{"option":"Vaginal misoprostol","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the definition of small for gestational age fetuses?","answers":[{"option":"Abdominal circumference less than the 10th centile","bool":false},{"option":"Weight more than 90th centile for the appropriate gestational age","bool":false},{"option":"Pathological process restricting fetal growth","bool":false},{"option":"Weight less than 10th centile for the appropriate gestational age","bool":true},{"option":"Birth weight less than 2500g","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 24-year-old woman undergoes laparoscopy as part of evaluation for her chronic pelvic pain. Multiple red-blue nodules are found on her uterine ligaments. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Metastases","bool":false},{"option":"Endometriosis","bool":true},{"option":"Adenomyosis","bool":false},{"option":"Peritoneal tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Ovarian cysts","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A neonate is not showing any respiratory efforts after appropriate stimulation. What is the next best thing to do?","answers":[{"option":"Positive pressure ventilation","bool":true},{"option":"Chest compressions","bool":false},{"option":"Endotracheal intubation","bool":false},{"option":"Assess after 1 minute","bool":false},{"option":"Airway suctioning","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A mother presents with fever and a tense uterus after delivering her baby via C-section. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Uterine atony","bool":false},{"option":"Couvelaire uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Postpartum endometritis","bool":true},{"option":"Psychosomatic pain","bool":false},{"option":"Peritonitis","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A pregnant woman is diagnosed with hepatitis B. What is the odd statement regarding her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Active immunization safe in pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Neonate given active and passive immunization","bool":false},{"option":"High risk women should be counselled and vaccinated before pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Neonatal vaccine is given in 3 doses","bool":false},{"option":"Breastfeeding is completely contraindicated","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A baby is born at term weighing 3 kg. The mother is concerned that she does not have enough milk. What will be the appropriate advice for her?","answers":[{"option":"Reassure/ advise to continue breast feeding","bool":true},{"option":"Give parenteral nutrition to the baby","bool":false},{"option":"Give excess water","bool":false},{"option":"Switch to formula milk","bool":false},{"option":"Start weaning with soft foods","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 29-year-old married lady presents to the outpatient clinic with complaints of left breast swelling for the past 4 months. Family history is positive for breast and ovarian malignancy. On local examination, a large ulcerated swelling measuring 15x12x10 cm is detected in the left breast. The mass was firm to soft in consistency, emitting putrid-smelling discharge, non-tender to touch, and bosselated leaf-like appearance with erythema of surrounding skin. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Malignant phyllodes tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Paget disease of the breast","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroadenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Benign phyllodes tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Galactocele of the left breast","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A female is brought by her parents to the local clinic with a complaint of excessive hair growth with a male-pattern distribution including axillae, face, chest, and abdomen. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hypertrichosis","bool":false},{"option":"Folliculitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Virilization","bool":false},{"option":"Hirsutism","bool":true}]},{"id":75,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 32-year-old female, gravida 2 para 1 presents to the maternity clinic for her antenatal visit. She has a mitral valve replacement done previously. Which department will be particularly involved in her antenatal care?","answers":[{"option":"Plastic surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiology","bool":true},{"option":"Thoracic surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Psychiatry","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonology","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 52-year-old female presents to the clinic with complaints of hot flushes and sweating. Which of the following can cause these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"High FSH","bool":true},{"option":"Low LH","bool":false},{"option":"Low FSH","bool":false},{"option":"Low FSH and LH","bool":false},{"option":"High LH","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A female presents to the clinic with complaints of lower abdominal pain and a greenish-yellow vaginal discharge. On speculum examination, the cervix appears red with multiple punctate hemorrhages. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":true},{"option":"Bacterial vaginosis","bool":false},{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Atrophic vaginitis","bool":false},{"option":"Vaginal candidiasis","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 28 weeks pregnant female, with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) is in labor. She is 6 cm dilated. How will you monitor fetal distress?","answers":[{"option":"Umbilical artery Doppler","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiotocography (CTG)","bool":true},{"option":"Chorionic villus sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Cord blood sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal scalp blood testing","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the most common genetic mutation associated with endometrial hyperplasia?","answers":[{"option":"ERAS","bool":false},{"option":"PIK3CA","bool":false},{"option":"TP53","bool":false},{"option":"PTEN","bool":true},{"option":"RB","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 33-year-old woman presents to the clinic with complaints of an inability to conceive for the past 3 years despite regular unprotected intercourse. She also complains of recurrent lower abdominal bleeding and dyspareunia. What is the gold-standard investigation for establishing a diagnosis is this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false},{"option":"Laparoscopy","bool":true},{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) scan","bool":false},{"option":"Examination under anesthesia (EUA)","bool":false},{"option":"Hysteroscopy and biopsy","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the most common genetic mutation seen in low-grade serous ovarian carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"PTEN","bool":false},{"option":"KRAS","bool":true},{"option":"BRAC1/2","bool":false},{"option":"TP53","bool":false},{"option":"PIK3CA","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the appropriate histological classification of struma ovarii tumor?","answers":[{"option":"Germ cell tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Sex-cord stromal tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Dysgerminoma","bool":false},{"option":"Surface epithelial tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Mesothelial tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 34-year-old male underwent a bilateral orchiectomy for a paratesticular mass, and histopathological analysis reveals sheets of pale cells with clear cytoplasm and central nuclei. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Embryonal cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Yolk sac tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Dysgerminoma","bool":false},{"option":"Seminoma","bool":true},{"option":"Sertoli-Leydig cell tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following cell surface markers is not expressed by seminoma?","answers":[{"option":"NANOG","bool":false},{"option":"OCT3/4","bool":false},{"option":"Placental alkaline phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"CD30","bool":true},{"option":"KIT","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the most specific marker on immunostaining in yolk sac tumors?","answers":[{"option":"LDH","bool":false},{"option":"hcG","bool":false},{"option":"CA-125","bool":false},{"option":"AFP","bool":true},{"option":"KIT","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Endodermal sinus tumors are most common in which age group?","answers":[{"option":"Young adults","bool":false},{"option":"Teenagers","bool":false},{"option":"Middle aged males","bool":false},{"option":"Infants","bool":true},{"option":"Elderly","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the total number of features required to establish a diagnosis of fibrocystic breast changes?","answers":[{"option":"4","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":true},{"option":"1","bool":false},{"option":"5","bool":false},{"option":"2","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A woman presents to the clinic with a large breast mass with shiny taut overlying skin and a bosselated surface. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Invasive lobular carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Phyllodes tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Inflammatory breast carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroadenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrocystic breast disease","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 24-year-old female presents to the clinic with 6 weeks of amenorrhea. Ultrasound shows an empty uterus with an adnexal sac, absent fetal heart sounds, and fluid in the cul-de-sac measuring approximately 20 ml. What is the appropriate management?","answers":[{"option":"Laparoscopic salpingectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Salpingotomy","bool":false},{"option":"Dilation and evacuation (D&E)","bool":false},{"option":"Expectant","bool":true},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the main mechanism of action of COCPs?","answers":[{"option":"Kills sperm prior to entry in fallopian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Negative feedback on anterior pituitary","bool":true},{"option":"Thicken cervical mucus to prevent passage fo sperm","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrial atorphy","bool":false},{"option":"Suppress menstruation","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A woman on combined oral contraceptive pills misses two consecutive pills during the third week. What is the appropriate step for minimizing the risk of pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Emergency contraceptive if unprotected intercourse performed","bool":false},{"option":"No need for emergency contraceptive","bool":false},{"option":"Omit pill-free interval and start new pack afterwards","bool":true},{"option":"Intercourse should be avoided for seven days","bool":false},{"option":"Take rest of the pills as usual","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 52-year-old woman consults her gynecologist with concerns regarding recurrent hot flushes and sweating for the past month. What is the cause of these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Elevated inhibin levels","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of estrogen secretion","bool":true},{"option":"Decrease in progesterone levels","bool":false},{"option":"Raised testosterone levels","bool":false},{"option":"Raised FSH and LH levels","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the below-enlisted is associated with oligohydramnios?","answers":[{"option":"Anencephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"NSAIDs","bool":true},{"option":"Lithium","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A young female underwent a dilation and curettage (D&C) at a local maternity clinic for incomplete abortion. What is the long-term complication of this procedure?","answers":[{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Endometritis","bool":false},{"option":"Ashermann syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":95,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 34-year-old primigravida female delivers a healthy term baby vaginally and enters the third stage of labor. She delivers a complete placenta with a loss of 700 ml of blood. What investigation should be ordered in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Serum beta-hcG levels","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Urinalysis","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulation profile","bool":true},{"option":"Complete blood count (CBC)","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 75-year-old female presents to the clinic with a mass on her vulva. On examination, the mass measures 1 cm in diameter. What is the appropriate stage?","answers":[{"option":"IIB","bool":false},{"option":"I","bool":true},{"option":"II","bool":false},{"option":"IIIC","bool":false},{"option":"IIIA","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the single best indicator of a healthy child?","answers":[{"option":"Weight","bool":true},{"option":"Milestones","bool":false},{"option":"Development","bool":false},{"option":"Occipito-frontal circumference (OFC)","bool":false},{"option":"Height","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A primigravida female presents for her regular antenatal visit at the 28th week of gestation. Her symphysio-fundal height (SFH) measures 24 cm. What is the appropriate investigation in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Fetal fibronectin levels","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Amniotic fluid sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic ultrasound","bool":true},{"option":"No investigation needed","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"The World Health Organization classifies endometrial hyperplasia into how many categories?","answers":[{"option":"2","bool":true},{"option":"1","bool":false},{"option":"4","bool":false},{"option":"5","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the best parameter to assess fetoplacental perfusion?","answers":[{"option":"Umbilical artery Doppler","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebroplacental ratio","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine artery Doppler","bool":false},{"option":"Biophysical profile","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiotocography","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 28-year-old female presents for her regular antenatal visit at the 38th week of gestation. Examination confirms her pregnancy has a breech presentation. What is the next appropriate step?","answers":[{"option":"Counsel for elective cesarean section","bool":false},{"option":"Induce labor","bool":false},{"option":"Wait for spontaneous labor","bool":false},{"option":"External cephalic version","bool":true},{"option":"Emergency cesarean section","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A young female presents to the emergency room at the 31st week of gestation with 2/10 contractions lasting for 15-20 seconds each. Pelvic examination reveals full dilation and effacement. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"False labor","bool":false},{"option":"Prelabor rupture of membranes","bool":false},{"option":"Spontaneous miscarriage","bool":false},{"option":"Abortion","bool":false},{"option":"Preterm labor","bool":true}]},{"id":103,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 30-year-old female presents to the labor room at the 38th week of gestation with regular painful uterine contractions 4/10 lasting for 40-50 seconds each. Pelvic examination reveals effacement with 3-4 cm dilation. Examination 2 hours later reveals similar findings, and an emergency lower-segment cesarean section is performed. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cervical dystocia","bool":false},{"option":"Primary arrest of labor","bool":false},{"option":"Dysfunctional uterine activity","bool":false},{"option":"Face presentation","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalopelvic disproportion","bool":true}]},{"id":104,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 34 weeks pregnant female presents to the antenatal clinic for her regular checkup. Her prior antenatal workup reviews hemoglobin electrophoresis for sickle-cell disease. What fetal complication can most likely occur?","answers":[{"option":"Sickle-cell crisis","bool":false},{"option":"Pre-eclampsia","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal growth restriction","bool":true},{"option":"Deep vein thrombosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Spermatocytic seminoma differs from classic seminoma as the former shows which of the following features?","answers":[{"option":"Good prognosis","bool":true},{"option":"Rapid cell growth","bool":false},{"option":"Young age group","bool":false},{"option":"Intertubular germ cell neoplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Large tumor masses","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"The low grade serous carcinoma of the ovary carry highest frequency of mutation in which of the following genes?","answers":[{"option":"BRCA1","bool":false},{"option":"RB","bool":false},{"option":"BRAF","bool":false},{"option":"KRAS","bool":true},{"option":"TP53","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 33-year-old woman presents to the clinic with pain in her pelvic region. The doctor advises an ultrasound to investigate the cause and it shows a 10 cm, fluid-filled, ovarian cyst. Histopathology shows cyst lined by stratified squamous epithelium with hair, sebaceous glands, and neural tissue. Which of the following neoplasms is most likely?","answers":[{"option":"Immature teratoma","bool":false},{"option":"Mucus cyst adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Mature teratoma","bool":true},{"option":"Mucus cyst adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Dysgermionoma","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the cause of hirsutism in a patient with polycystic ovarian syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Androgen excess","bool":true},{"option":"Estrogen deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Drug use","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen excess","bool":false},{"option":"Androgen deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 25-year-old woman, G1P0, presents for her regular antenatal checkup at the 24th week of pregnancy. Her serum hemoglobin level is 8.9 g/dL. She was diagnosed with thalassemia minor during her childhood. What is the next step in her antenatal management?","answers":[{"option":"Improve diet","bool":false},{"option":"Parenteral iron replacement","bool":false},{"option":"Call for routine checkup","bool":false},{"option":"Hb electrophoresis of husband","bool":true},{"option":"Oral iron supplements","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A baby is delivered with skin covered by a greenish material. What is the potential complication?","answers":[{"option":"Atelectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Meconium aspiration syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A baby is delivered at a low birth weight of 1.5 kg. Which complication is the baby at a high risk of?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypocalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothermia","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperthermia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglycemia","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is the best indicator of chronic fetal hypoxia?","answers":[{"option":"Fetal movement","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal tone","bool":false},{"option":"Amniotic fluid reduction","bool":true},{"option":"Fetal measurements","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal heart rate","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is not commonly used for the treatment of hirsutism?","answers":[{"option":"Electrolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Laser therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Eflornithine","bool":false},{"option":"Clomiphene","bool":true},{"option":"Cyproterone acetate","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"30-year-old primigravida presents to the clinic for antenatal care at 32 weeks gestation. Her symphysiofundal height (SFH) is 28 cm and her ultrasound shows a baby that is small for gestational age (SGA). What is the definition of such a baby?","answers":[{"option":"Fetus with abdominal circumference or estimated fetal weight (EFW) less than 10th centile for gestational age","bool":true},{"option":"Fetus with abdominal circumference or estimated fetal weight (EFW) less than 50th centile for gestational age","bool":false},{"option":"Fetus with abdominal circumference or estimated fetal weight (EFW) less than 5th centile for gestational age","bool":false},{"option":"Fetus with abdominal circumference or estimated fetal weight (EFW) less than 70th centile for gestational age","bool":false},{"option":"Fetus with abdominal circumference or estimated fetal weight (EFW) less than 90th centile for gestational age","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Spiral arteries become more convoluted, endometrium growth occurs, and fluid secretion begins. What phase of the menstrual cycle is this?","answers":[{"option":"Proliferative phase","bool":false},{"option":"Luteal phase","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperproliferative phase","bool":false},{"option":"Menstrual phase","bool":false},{"option":"Follicular phase","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is a major synthetic estrogen?","answers":[{"option":"Ethinyl estradiol","bool":true},{"option":"Estriol","bool":false},{"option":"Estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylstilbestrol","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 23-year-old female presents to the clinic with a complaint of vaginal discharge for the past three days. On pelvic examination, the discharge is white in color and has a foul fishy odor. She is diagnosed with bacterial vaginosis. Which of the following is/are the most appropriate choice of medication(s) for bacterial vaginosis?","answers":[{"option":"Topical antifungals","bool":false},{"option":"Ketoconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Clindamycin and flagyl","bool":true},{"option":"Third generation cephalosporins","bool":false},{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"According to the latest classification by the World Health Organisation (WHO), how many categories of endometrial hyperplasia are recognized?","answers":[{"option":"Two","bool":true},{"option":"Six","bool":false},{"option":"Three","bool":false},{"option":"Five","bool":false},{"option":"Four","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"During operative vaginal delivery, what should be the opening vacuum pressure of the ventouse cup?","answers":[{"option":"0.6-0.8 kg/cm2","bool":true},{"option":"0.4-0.6 kg/cm2","bool":false},{"option":"0.7-0.9 kg/cm2","bool":false},{"option":"0.2-0.4 kg/cm2","bool":false},{"option":"0.3-0.5 kg/cm2","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of combined oral contraceptives?","answers":[{"option":"Increases LH to FSH ratio","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits estrogen action","bool":false},{"option":"Suppress release of FSH and LH from pituitary gland","bool":true},{"option":"Leads to follicle degeneration.","bool":false},{"option":"Positive feedback to hypothalamic pituitary axis","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 28-year-old woman presents with a complaint of lower abdominal pain persisting for 6 months. On examination, purulent discharge is noted from inside the cervix. The patient reports experiencing dyspareunia and irregular menstrual cycles. Which of the following is the most likely cause of her illness?","answers":[{"option":"Cervical polyps","bool":false},{"option":"Endometriosis","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine fibroids","bool":false},{"option":"Ovarian cysts","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic inflammatory disease (PID)","bool":true}]},{"id":122,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 25-year-old woman with amenorrhea for 6 months was rushed to the emergency with sudden onset of abdominal pain and signs of hypovolemic shock. The doctor suspects it to be a case of ruptured ectopic pregnancy. What is the next best step in management?","answers":[{"option":"Laparotomy with salpingectomy","bool":true},{"option":"Stabilize and infuse low molecular weight heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Stabilize and monitor the hemodynamic status","bool":false},{"option":"Laparotomy with salpingostomy","bool":false},{"option":"Laparoscopy and salpingectomy","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A normotensive 2nd gravida presents to the outpatient department at 36 weeks of pregnancy with breech presentation. Her first delivery was uneventful. Now her ultrasound shows a fetus with flexed breech presentation, fundo posterior placenta and an estimated fetal weight of 3000(+/-)200 grams. What can she be offered?","answers":[{"option":"External cephalic version","bool":true},{"option":"Elective caesarean section","bool":false},{"option":"Wait for spontaneous version","bool":false},{"option":"Emergency caesarean section","bool":false},{"option":"Trial of breech delivery","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A normotensive 2nd gravida presents to the outpatient department at 36 weeks of pregnancy with breech presentation. Her first delivery was uneventful. Now her ultrasound shows a fetus with a flexed breech presentation, fundo posterior placenta, and an estimated fetal weight of 3000(+/-)200 grams. External cephalic version (ECV) fails. What alternative option can be offered to manage the breech presentation?","answers":[{"option":"Elective caesarean section","bool":true},{"option":"Retry external cephalic version","bool":false},{"option":"Wait for spontaneous version","bool":false},{"option":"Trial of breech delivery","bool":false},{"option":"Emergency caesarean section","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is a potential complication associated with assisted breech delivery?","answers":[{"option":"Uterine rupture","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal bradycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Cord prolapse","bool":true},{"option":"Placenta previa","bool":false},{"option":"Shoulder dystocia","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 60-year-old female presents with a palpable breast mass that she noticed a few weeks ago. Upon examination, the mass appears to have shiny skin and is showing signs of impending ulceration. The patient reports a rapidly growing lump with distinct borders. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Intraductal papilloma","bool":false},{"option":"Ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS)","bool":false},{"option":"Phyllodes tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Fibroadenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Invasive ductal carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the most common malignant para testicular tumour in adults?","answers":[{"option":"Teratoma","bool":false},{"option":"Liposarcoma","bool":true},{"option":"Seminoma","bool":false},{"option":"Leydig cell tumour","bool":false},{"option":"Rhabdomyosarcoma","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"An 11-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department with a testicular mass. Laboratory tests show an elevated level of alpha-fetoprotein (AFP). Histopathology report reveals schiller-duval bodies. The parents report that the mass has been growing rapidly. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Leydig cell tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Seminoma","bool":false},{"option":"Teratoma","bool":false},{"option":"Yolk sac tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Rhabdomyosarcoma","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is another name for Bowen's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Cervical intraepithelial neoplasia (CIN)","bool":false},{"option":"Vaginal intraepithelial neoplasia (VAIN)","bool":false},{"option":"melanoma","bool":false},{"option":"Vulvar intraepithelial neoplasia (VIN)","bool":true},{"option":"Lichen sclerosus","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 25-year-old primigravida presents to the outpatient department at 8 weeks of gestation with complaints of vaginal bleeding and lower abdominal pain. On examination, cervical os is closed, and fetal heartbeat is healthy. Which of the following is the appropriate management protocol?","answers":[{"option":"Observation with regular follow-up and reassurance","bool":true},{"option":"Serial ultrasound monitoring","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Dilatation and curettage","bool":false},{"option":"Immediate hospitalization for bed rest","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"The Safe Motherhood initiative was launched by the World Health Organisation (WHO) to ensure a safe outcome of pregnancy for both mother and child. which of the following is the first step of the safe motherhood initiative?","answers":[{"option":"Abortion rights","bool":false},{"option":"Antenatal care","bool":false},{"option":"Clean, safe delivery","bool":false},{"option":"Essential obstretic care","bool":false},{"option":"Family planning","bool":true}]},{"id":132,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 28-year-old woman presents with a 3-year history of primary infertility, dyspareunia, and cyclic lower abdominal pain. She describes heavy and prolonged menstrual bleeding. Her menstrual cycles are irregular, and she reports pain during bowel movements. In this scenario, what is the best investigation to diagnose her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Hormonal profile","bool":false},{"option":"Laparoscopy","bool":true},{"option":"Hysterosalpingography (HSG)","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrial biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Transvaginal ultrasound","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 40-year-old female is diagnosed with a primary ovarian tumour affecting both ovaries. which ovarian neoplasm is most commonly associated with bilaterality?","answers":[{"option":"Brenner tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Mucinous cystadenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Ovarian teratoma","bool":false},{"option":"Serous carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Epithelial ovarian cancer","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 40-year-old woman undergoes surgery for an ovarian mass, and the pathology report reveals struma ovarii. This tumour is histologically composed predominantly of which type of tissue?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrous tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Germ cell tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid tissue","bool":true},{"option":"Endometrial tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Ovarian stromal tissue","bool":false}]},{"id":135,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 35-year-old female, who is a smoker, presents with a painful breast. On examination, there is a palpable breast mass associated with skin dimpling and nipple retraction. She reports occasional bloody nipple discharge. Which of the following is a key morphological feature of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Enlarged axillary lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Keratinizing squamous metaplasia of lactiferous ducts","bool":true},{"option":"Microcalcifications","bool":false},{"option":"Atypical ductal hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Atypical lobular hyperplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":136,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"An 18-year-old female presents with primary amenorrhea. She exhibits normal secondary sexual characteristics. On examination, a blind uterus is observed. Ultrasound scan shows normal functioning ovaries. which of the following is the likely cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Androgen Insensitivity Syndrome (AIS)","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic Ovary Syndrome (PCOS)","bool":false},{"option":"Turner syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Mayer-rokitansky-küster-hauser (MRKH) syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Asherman's syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":137,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following drug is used for the treatment of hirsutism?","answers":[{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Fluoxetine","bool":false},{"option":"Clomiphene","bool":false},{"option":"Metformin","bool":false},{"option":"Cyproterone acetate","bool":true}]},{"id":138,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is a topical drug used for the treatment of hirsutism?","answers":[{"option":"Minoxidil","bool":false},{"option":"Clindamycin","bool":false},{"option":"Eflornithine","bool":true},{"option":"Finasteride","bool":false},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A female presents with 6 weeks of amenorrhea, an empty gestational sac, fluid in the cul-de-sac and absent fetal heart sounds. Additionally, beta-hCG levels are undetectable. What is the appropriate management?","answers":[{"option":"Immediate laparotomy","bool":false},{"option":"Dilatation and curettage (D&C)","bool":false},{"option":"Methotrexate administration","bool":false},{"option":"Laparoscopic salpingostomy","bool":false},{"option":"Supportive management","bool":true}]},{"id":140,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the hormone responsible for milk secretion?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":true},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":141,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"As per the national breastfeeding policy for health facilities, when should breastfeeding be initiated in an infant for optimal breastfeeding?","answers":[{"option":"Within 1 hour after birth","bool":false},{"option":"Soon after birth","bool":false},{"option":"Start within 6 hours after birth","bool":false},{"option":"Initiate within 12 hours","bool":false},{"option":"Begin within half an hour after birth","bool":true}]},{"id":142,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"In a newborn, what is the most severe complication associated with jaundice?","answers":[{"option":"Renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Kernicterus","bool":true},{"option":"Acute pancreatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cholelithiasis","bool":false}]},{"id":143,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following statements correctly defines the maternal mortality ratio?","answers":[{"option":"The rate of stillbirths per 1,000 pregnancies","bool":false},{"option":"The ratio of live births to total births in a given population","bool":false},{"option":"The number of deaths of mothers per 100,000 live births in the given time period","bool":true},{"option":"The number of deaths of infants under one year of age per 1,000 live births in the given time period","bool":false},{"option":"The percentage of pregnancies that end in abortion","bool":false}]},{"id":144,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 26-year-old woman has a lump in her left breast. On physical examination, the physician finds an irregular, firm, 2 cm mass in the upper inner quadrant of the breast. A fine needle aspirate of the mass shows carcinoma. The patient's 30-year-old sister was recently diagnosed with ovarian cancer. Which of the following genes is most commonly associated with ovarian cancer?","answers":[{"option":"BRCA1","bool":true},{"option":"BARCA2","bool":false},{"option":"ERBB2 (growth factor receptor gene)","bool":false},{"option":"EGF (epidermal growth factor gene)","bool":false},{"option":"HSTI (fibroblast growth factor gene)","bool":false}]},{"id":145,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 25-year-old female presents with abdominal pain and an adnexal mass. Imaging studies reveal an ovarian tumor. Histopathological examination demonstrates a yellow white soft and fleshy tumor with a uniform population of large, round cells, and well-defined boundaries with clear cytoplasm and central nuclei. Histopathologists further noticed its striking similarity with testicular seminoma. Which of the following is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Mucinous cystadenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrioid carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Brenner tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Dysgerminoma","bool":true},{"option":"Teratoma","bool":false}]},{"id":146,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 3-week-old infant presents with jaundice persisting for 3 days. On examination, the gallbladder is non-palpable. The infant has clay-coloured stools, dark urine, and an enlarged liver. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Biliary atresia","bool":true},{"option":"Alagille syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Neonatal sepsis","bool":false},{"option":"Neonatal hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Choledochal cyst","bool":false}]},{"id":147,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"According to the World Health Organisation (WHO), during which week of gestation is a baby most perceptible to death if born prematurely in developing countries?","answers":[{"option":"Less than 28th week","bool":true},{"option":"Less than 30th week","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 36th week","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 32nd week","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 34th week","bool":false}]},{"id":148,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 30-year-old primigravida presents to the obstetrician in the 34th week of pregnancy. Hb electrophoresis reveals the presence of HbS. What fetal complication may occur?","answers":[{"option":"Neonatal respiratory distress syndrome (NRDS)","bool":false},{"option":"Intrauterine growth restriction (IUGR)","bool":true},{"option":"Macrosomia","bool":false},{"option":"Oligohydramnios","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral vein thrombosis","bool":false}]},{"id":149,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Why is liquid-based cytology considered better than a Pap smear?","answers":[{"option":"Increased sensitivity","bool":true},{"option":"Improved detection of abnormalities","bool":false},{"option":"Inexpensive","bool":false},{"option":"Less inadequate sample","bool":false},{"option":"Woman has less anxiety","bool":false}]},{"id":150,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 28-year-old woman is diagnosed with a molar pregnancy which is followed by a suction and curettage procedure. What is the appropriate follow-up plan for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Monthly pelvic ultrasound for the next 6 months","bool":false},{"option":"Referral to a fertility specialist for in vitro fertilization (IVF)","bool":false},{"option":"Immediate planning for the next pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Weekly beta-hcg monitoring until levels normalize","bool":true},{"option":"Initiation of oral contraceptive pills for 3 months","bool":false}]},{"id":151,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 7-year-old male child is brought to the clinic due to an empty hemiscrotum. During the examination, the testis is found in the inguinal canal. However, upon gently manipulating the testis, it can be relocated to the scrotum. What is the most probable diagnosis for the male child?","answers":[{"option":"Varicocele","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocele","bool":false},{"option":"Testicular torsion","bool":false},{"option":"Retractable testis","bool":true},{"option":"Cryptorchidism","bool":false}]},{"id":152,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 55-year-old menopausal woman is receiving hormone replacement therapy (HRT) for symptom management. She expresses concern about the risk of endometrial carcinoma associated with HRT. What can be recommended to reduce the risk of endometrial carcinoma in post menopausal women receiving hormone replacement therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Increase the dosage of estrogen in the hormone replacement therapy regimen","bool":false},{"option":"Initiate a low-fat diet to reduce estrogen levels","bool":false},{"option":"Combine estrogen with progesterone in the hormone replacement therapy regimen","bool":true},{"option":"Discontinue hormone replacement therapy immediately","bool":false},{"option":"Undergo endometrial biopsy every month","bool":false}]},{"id":153,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 32-year-old woman presents with intermenstrual bleeding (IMB), and subfertility. A 2 cm endometrial polyp is seen on pelvic ultrasound. What is the most appropriate next step in the management?","answers":[{"option":"Saline infusion sonohysterography (SIS)","bool":false},{"option":"Outpatient hysteroscopy (OPH)","bool":true},{"option":"Initiate empirical treatment with antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Prescribe hormonal contraceptives for endometrial stabilization","bool":false},{"option":"Laparoscopy","bool":false}]},{"id":154,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A woman having a history of a recent road traffic accident (RTA) presents with a painless palpable breast mass. Imaging reveals fat necrosis. What is the likely cause of the breast mass?","answers":[{"option":"Traumatic fat necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Inflammatory breast cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoma","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroadenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Breast abscess","bool":false}]},{"id":155,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 51-year-old female presents with hot flushes and sweats. These symptoms are most likely due to fluctuations in the levels of which hormone?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Thyroid hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false}]},{"id":156,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 28-year-old gravida 3+0 presents to the obstetrician clinic for her routine pregnancy checkup. Her ultrasound reveals decreased amniotic fluid levels, indicating oligohydramnios. Which of the following medications is most likely associated with this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Ibuprofen","bool":true},{"option":"Vasopressin","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Indomethacin","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false}]},{"id":157,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 28-year-old gravida 2+0 presents to the obstetric clinic at the 20th week of gestation for a prenatal checkup. She has a history of preterm delivery. At which week of gestation is fetal fibronectin typically checked to assess the risk of preterm delivery in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"22-26-weeks","bool":false},{"option":"30-36 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"16-20 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"18-24 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"22-36 weeks","bool":true}]},{"id":158,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 35-year-old male presented to a subfertility clinic. Investigations reveal the pH of semen as 7.4, a volume of 2.0 ml, a total sperm count of 34 x 10^6/ml, progressive motility of 5%, and sperm morphology of 8%. What is the abnormality seen in this semen report?","answers":[{"option":"Asthenospermia","bool":true},{"option":"Oligozoospermia","bool":false},{"option":"Azoospermia","bool":false},{"option":"Normozoospermia","bool":false},{"option":"Teratozoospermia","bool":false}]},{"id":159,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 23-year-old primigravida is admitted to the labor room with regular contractions. On examination, her cervix is found to be 7 cm dilated. The healthcare provider notes that cervical dilatation occurs at 1 cm/hour. Which of the following is the appropriate next step for management?","answers":[{"option":"Prepare for emergency cesarian section","bool":false},{"option":"Administer oxytocin to augment contractions","bool":false},{"option":"Perform amniotomy","bool":false},{"option":"One on one midwifery care","bool":true},{"option":"Administer epidural analgesia for pain relief","bool":false}]},{"id":160,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 32-year-old pregnant female, gravida 4 para 3+0, presents to the emergency department with sudden, severe abdominal pain. On examination, there is no uterine contour palpable, and fetal heart sounds (FHS) are absent. She had a previous classical uterine incision. Which of the following is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ovarian torsion","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine rupture","bool":true},{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Placental abruption","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic inflammatory disease","bool":false}]},{"id":161,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A newborn is delivered with forceps assistance. upon neonatal examination, a swelling is noted on the parietal bone. The infant is otherwise well and shows no signs of distress. Which of the following is the appropriate management for the neonate?","answers":[{"option":"Referral to a neurosurgeon for further evaluation","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Application of ice packs to reduce swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Observation, as it will resolve on its own","bool":true},{"option":"Surgical evacuation by aspiration","bool":false}]},{"id":162,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 25-year-old primigravida admitted to the labour room of civil hospital karachi is in the second stage of labour for 2.5 hours. Her midwife informs the obstetrician of the arrest of descent of the fetal head. On examination, the head is 0/5 palpable, the cervix is fully dilated and the membranes ruptured, caput and moulding is moderate. What is the appropriate course of action?","answers":[{"option":"Encourage spontaneous pushing and wait for descent","bool":false},{"option":"Emergency cesarean section","bool":false},{"option":"Perform uterine massage","bool":false},{"option":"Application of keilland forceps to assist with descent","bool":true},{"option":"Administer oxytocin to enhance uterine contractions","bool":false}]},{"id":163,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 24-year-old gravida 2 para 1+0 comes for a checkup at the 28th week of gestation. Her symphysis-fundal height (SFH) measures 24 cm. How should fetal growth be further assessed?","answers":[{"option":"Advising anomaly scan","bool":false},{"option":"Performing a doppler ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Conducting a dating scan","bool":false},{"option":"Recommending a growth scan","bool":true},{"option":"Ordering a biophysical profile","bool":false}]},{"id":164,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 30-year-old primigravida comes to the outpatient department at 35 weeks gestation with a complete blood count (CBC) revealing a platelet count of 40,000. She has a known history of immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP). What is the next step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Administration of intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG)","bool":false},{"option":"Close monitoring without immediate intervention","bool":true},{"option":"Commencement of corticosteroid therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Immediate induction of labor","bool":false},{"option":"Emergency cesarean section","bool":false}]},{"id":165,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 24-year-old primigravida comes at 38 weeks with regular painful uterine contractions.  The cervical dilation is 1.5 cm for 4 hours. An emergency cesarean section is performed, and a baby weighing 3 kg is delivered. What could be the reason for the arrest of labour?","answers":[{"option":"Placenta previa","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine atony","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal exhaustion","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalopelvic disproportion","bool":true},{"option":"Placental abruption","bool":false}]},{"id":166,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 32-year-old pregnant female at 34 weeks gestation presents to the emergency room with sudden onset abdominal pain and mild vaginal bleeding. On examination, her blood pressure is measured at 60/20, pulse rate is 140, and fetal heart sounds are absent. What complication has she likely gone into?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiogenic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Septic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Hypovolemic shock","bool":true},{"option":"Neurogenic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC)","bool":false}]},{"id":167,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 28-year-old woman undergoes an elective cesarean section due to breech presentation at 39 weeks of gestation. The procedure is uneventful, and the baby is delivered with an Apgar score of 9 at 1 minute. However, shortly after placental removal, the patient begins to experience profuse postpartum haemorrhage. The estimated blood loss reaches 2500 ml, prompting the healthcare provider to notify a senior medical colleague. What is the appropriate next step in managing this situation?","answers":[{"option":"Immediate blood transfusion","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of large bore cannulation","bool":false},{"option":"Preparation for emergency hysterectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Performing a bimanual uterine massage","bool":true},{"option":"Initiation of intravenous antibiotics","bool":false}]},{"id":168,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 32-year-old pregnant woman at 38 weeks gestation presents to the emergency room with sudden onset abdominal pain and mild vaginal bleeding. She was previously healthy during her pregnancy, but now her blood pressure is dropping, and fetal heart sounds are becoming faint on continuous fetal monitoring (CTG). Which of the following is the most likely cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Cord prolapse","bool":false},{"option":"Placenta previa","bool":false},{"option":"Vasa previa","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine rupture","bool":false},{"option":"Abruptio placenta","bool":true}]},{"id":169,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 30-year-old woman, gravida 3 para 1+1, presents for her first antenatal booking at 6 weeks of gestation. She has a history of Rhesus isoimmunization. The baby's father is Rh positive. What should be the next step in the management?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound to assess the viability of the fetus","bool":false},{"option":"Recommend genetic counseling to assess the risk of Rhesus isoimmunization in the current pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Monitoring antibody levels every 2–4  weeks from booking.","bool":true},{"option":"Prescribe a prenatal vitamin supplement with an emphasis on folic acid intake","bool":false},{"option":"Initiate early administration of Rh immunoglobulin","bool":false}]},{"id":170,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 34-year-old primigravida is undergoing an elective cesarean section due to breech presentation. Following delivery, the newborn shows signs of tachypnea. What is the appropriate management for the neonate?","answers":[{"option":"Encourage breastfeeding to promote natural lung expansion","bool":false},{"option":"Provide supplemental oxygen as required","bool":true},{"option":"Administer intravenous antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Administer intravenous prednisolone","bool":false},{"option":"Transfer the baby to the neonatal intensive care unit (NICU)","bool":false}]},{"id":171,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 30-year-old grand multipara delivered her baby at home with the assistance of a midwife. Four hours post-delivery, she presents to the emergency department with tachypnoea, tachycardia, hypotension, and severe bleeding. Which of the following is the first step in the management of postpartum haemorrhage?","answers":[{"option":"Rapid infusion with fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid infusion of epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Bimanual compression of uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Administer uterotonic agents","bool":false},{"option":"Call for senior help","bool":true}]},{"id":172,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"In terms of development, when does the growth spurt typically occur in males compared to females?","answers":[{"option":"Males experience the growth spurt approximately 3 years later than females","bool":false},{"option":"Males experience the growth spurt around the same time as females, but it lasts for a shorter duration","bool":false},{"option":"Males experience the growth spurt approximately 1-2 years earlier than females","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs concurrently with females during puberty","bool":false},{"option":"Males experience the growth spurt approximately 1-2 years later than females","bool":true}]},{"id":173,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 32-year-old woman has just delivered her baby vaginally. The placenta was expelled spontaneously, and there were no apparent injuries during the delivery. However, she is now experiencing postpartum haemorrhage with continuous bleeding, last estimated as 700ml. Which of the following investigations should be considered for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Repeat blood typing and crossmatching","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulation profile to evaluate for any clotting abnormalities","bool":true},{"option":"Doppler ultrasound to evaluate uterine blood flow","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic ultrasound to assess for retained placental fragments","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count (CBC) to assess for anemia and blood loss","bool":false}]},{"id":174,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A newborn, now on the third day of birth, has a bilirubin level of 18 mg/dL. Jaundice was noted since the 25th hour after birth. Further investigations reveal the presence of microspherocytes and increased osmotic fragility. Which of the following is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"ABO incompatibility between the mother and the baby","bool":false},{"option":"Physiological jaundice of the newborn","bool":false},{"option":"Rh incompatibility between the mother and the baby","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Neonatal sepsis causing elevated bilirubin levels","bool":false}]},{"id":175,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 25-year-old female presents to the emergency department with complaints of labour pains. She also reported that she's 32 weeks pregnant. On examination, a white and foul-smelling discharge was seen. Which of the following is the likely cause of this patient's pre-term labour?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial vaginosis","bool":true},{"option":"Torch infections","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomonas vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Gardnerella vaginalis","bool":false}]},{"id":176,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 26-year-old female presents to the gynaecology clinic asking for emergency contraception three days after unprotected intercourse. Her ultrasound shows a normal uterus and ovaries. What should be the preferable treatment?","answers":[{"option":"OCPs","bool":false},{"option":"Cu-IUD","bool":true},{"option":"Mirena","bool":false},{"option":"Depo-provera","bool":false},{"option":"Levonorgestrel","bool":false}]},{"id":177,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 30-year-old gravida 3 para 1+1 presents to a clinic for a routine check-up at 20 weeks of gestation. She has a history of hypertension for ten years. Her recent ultrasound reveals asymmetrical fetal growth restriction. Which of the following is the most likely cause of fetal compromise?","answers":[{"option":"External trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Chromosomal defects","bool":false},{"option":"Inherited cause","bool":false},{"option":"Torch infection","bool":false},{"option":"Uteroplacental insufficiency","bool":true}]},{"id":178,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 35-year-old female presents to the clinic with complaints of dyspnea and early fatigability. She reports a history of heavy menstrual bleeding for one year. On examination, her uterus was of normal size, and no abnormality was noted. On transvaginal ultrasound, there was no pelvic abnormality. Her CBC showed haemoglobin of 7.5 g/dl. She has two children and does \r\nnot want to conceive at present. Which of the following is the most appropriate management for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Oral contraceptive pill","bool":false},{"option":"Levonorgestrel intrauterine system","bool":true},{"option":"Endometrial ablation","bool":false},{"option":"Iron and folic acid supplements","bool":false},{"option":"Hysterectomy","bool":false}]},{"id":179,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2019","question":"At a routine prenatal check-up, a 27-year-old woman, gravida 2 para 1, presents with a twin pregnancy at 37 weeks of gestation. An ultrasound scan reveals viable and healthy fetuses, with the first twin in a cephalic position and the second twin in a transverse position. Which of the following is the next step in management?","answers":[{"option":"Wait for spontaneous repositioning of the second twin","bool":false},{"option":"Schedule for cesarian delivery","bool":false},{"option":"External cephalic version","bool":true},{"option":"Internal cephalic version","bool":false},{"option":"Perform amniotomy","bool":false}]}]
export default arr